# **Brittiny Carvajal**

UI / UX Designer https://brittinycarvajal.github.io/portfolio/

916 990 3276 BrittinyCarvajal@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/brittiny-carvajal/

Energetic and devoted UI/UX Designer with real-world experience in practical design and coordination with Front-End Developers. Focused on customer first designs to define and design customer driven products. When I'm not designing you can find me dancing, reading, baking, or outside enjoying nature and doing sport rock climbing.

# Skills

User-Centered Design, Mobile-First Responsiveness, UI Design, Competitive Analysis Usability and Preference, User Testing, UI Elements and hierarchy, Design Principles, Principles of Integration, Creating Design Briefs, Building a Cohesive Brand

# **EXPERIENCE**

#### UI/UX Design Consultant, Freelance, Lehi, UT 1/2019-Present

- Critiqued designs for Front-End Developers establishing the most efficient user experience.
- Collaborated with Front End-Developers to define, develop, and maintain the desired design system causing a strong style guide.
- Audited applications to find inconsistency in design patterns.
- Design process covered: in person, phone, video, and message interviews, in depth user reviews research, creation of user personas, creation of color palettes, design of custom need UI components

Technology Used: In Vision, Sketch, Adove Xd, Flow Mapp, Flinto, Zeplin, Pen and Paper sketching, Usability Hub

# Interior Decorator, Freelance, International, 8/2011- Present

- Kept all projects under budget and delivered on time creating happy clients and free positive advertisement.
- Advised on size, shape, and color(s) of artwork to enhance home within their style guide causing commendations from every client for professionalism and creativity.

#### **Transfer Program Coordinator**, Zulu Marketing, Lehi, UT 5/2019-6/2019

- Supervised coworkers by helping develop their efficiency increasing completed transfers by 150%.
- Established effective communication lanes with vendors reducing transfer time by 30%.

#### Event Coordinator, Network Environmental Systems, Folsom, CA 9/2017-3/2018

- Assisted Advanced branding established on company blog bringing more clientele.
- Negotiated and coordinated with clients improving coworkers time-management and client's experience.

# **EDUCATION**

#### UI/UX Design, Career Foundry, 3/2019-7/2019

- Lead founder of product discovery and focal point researcher for research requests for a variety of projects.
- Organized own projects and worked efficiently with some oversight and heavy feedback from Mentor.
- Followed the User Experience Design Process developing the following:

*Skills*: User Psychology, User Research, User Personas, User Flows, User Flow Diagrams, User Testing, Mood Boards, Primary and Secondary themes, Actions, Alpha and Beta Testing, Responsive Design, Mobile First Driven Design, Wireframing including Low, Mid and High fidelity, Exploratory Sketching, Rapid Prototyping, Style Guide, Mockups, Review and Critiquing

# Web Design, Career Foundry, 8/2019-Present

- In the process of expanding web design knowledge.
- Creating responsive websites allowing me to bring my UI/UX designs to life.
- Leveraging frameworks such as bootstrap to create UI components.
- Learning Web Design Principles.

*Technology Used*: Html5, CSS, SCSS, Bootstrap, Angular, Node, Atom

# BA, English, Brigham Young University-Idaho.

- Practiced advanced principles of research to create a point of interest, learn about it in depth, and form an arguable opinion.
- Created strong written and oral communication skills across disciplines and teams.

# **PROJECTS**

Visit my website to take a look at my projects

# UI/UX Portfolio

Designed and delivered my personal portfolio in coordination with web developer.

# Wells Fargo App

Usability research was done on features that are required by users that the app does not have at the moment. Followed Design principles, designed, implemented, and delivered a complete addition of a very desired online banking app.

Leveraged tools following industry standards to expose assets and design mockups to developers.

Deliverables include design of wireframes, low, mid and high-fidelity mockups, user flow diagrams, creation of assets, custom icon creation, and interactive prototypes.

# Duolingo

Design a new comprehensive feature for the Duolingo app. The feature was chosen based on public feedback for the app found on the iOS App Store.

Deliverables include design of wireframes, low, mid and high-fidelity mockups, user flow diagrams, creation of assets, custom icon creation, and interactive prototypes.

#### Achieve it

The birth of a personal progress and user management app.

Conceptual and UI design of the app.

Created mood boards, user personas, and testing frameworks.

Deliverables include design of wireframes, low, mid and high-fidelity mockups, user flow diagrams, creation of assets, custom icon creation, and interactive prototypes.